

# Kody **Brown**

Software Architect

# **CONTACT ME**



(801) 310-1122



kody@vutiliti.com vutiliti.com



7065 S 5490 W West Jordan, UT 84081

### LINKS

GitHub, LinkedIn, Twitter, G+, FB kodybrown

#### **SKYPE**

wasatchwizard

#### WEB

kodybrown.com wasatchwizard.com

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

UI/UX Design
HTML5
CSS3
JavaScript
Responsive Web
REST / JSON
C# / ASP.NET



#### **ABOUT ME**

I am passionate about technology in all of its various forms. From running a large network of Bitcoin miners, building go-karts and electric scooters, to converting a 40-foot school bus to a mobile office and RV for the family. I am exceptionally skilled across the full stack of software development and Internet of Things (IoT) devices.

I take pride in transforming complex challenges into simple and elegant solutions, while maintaining an intuitive user experience. I can focus on the big picture while pacing myself and teams through the iterative development process, ensuring stable and extendable solutions.



## **EDUCATION**

**Business Management University of Phoenix** 

2002 - 2003

Robotics & Fabrication, Software Engineering Modesto Junior College

1992 - 1994



# **BUZZWORTHY**

#### Graduated high school early

Graduated high school at 15 years old and started attending college.

#### Essential C#

One of the technical editors of (three editions of) the Essential C# book by Mark Michaelis.

#### Patent #8,275,895

Steve Ellis and I are co-authors of "DHCP – Systems and methods for establishing a trusted dynamic host configuration protocol connection."

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Vutiliti, Inc. Web Architect

2015 - Present

Created responsive, mobile-first website using Angular.js and back-end services in Go. Worked with partners to solve enterprise issues using custom hardware and software designs to save companies money.

ConsultNet 2013 - 2016

# Web Architect (Consultant)

Created responsive websites using Angular.js, Node, Meteor, PhoneGap, Ember.js, and ASP.NET MVC while constantly adjusting to different teams and environments.

Venafi, Inc. 2008 - 2013

#### Web Architect

Led a team of six developers in the design and implementation of a complete web-based Certificate management console for Fortune 100 companies. It was completely extendable with over 130 plugins.

#### OneGreatFamily.com Web Architect

2006 - 2008

Led a team of four developers in creating a web-based genealogy website, including an online family tree, extensible dashboard, and widgets.

### LANDesk Software, Inc. Senior Software Engineer

2003 - 2006

As part of the ISV team I created various solutions based on customer need. so I was able to work in different areas of development. From Classic ASP to ASP.NET, and Windows CE/Mobile (C++) and BlackBerry (J2ME) devices. Created LANDesk Message-based SDK and Handheld Manager (which had over 1 million client installs).